[Music]
hello everyone this is Ravi welcome to
trienes tasa Advanced Training as you
all know I already published around 55
YouTube videos covering beginners level
intermediate level and advanced level
Concepts so from couple of videos
onwards I've started teaching you the
realtime scenarios where you might
encounter different types of obstacles
and challenges and how can we solve
those obstacles by using tricentis
Tas so this is our obstacle 14 in terms
of real time scenarios and this is our
lesson 56 in terms of overall Advanced
Training please do subscribe to the
channel click on Bell icon you'll
receive notifications whenever I publish
more videos please don't forget to like
and share the video thank
you in this lesson we're going to solve
an
obstacle by using the methods like
capturing Dynamic date and using date
expression to calculate the calendar
date date so now let us go and see what
is the obstacle that we need to solve
for so here is an obstacle named as
confusing dates and it is categorized as
medium let us go for
it let's see what's the obstacle so we
are going to generate a new date in the
US format by pressing the calendar
button this is our calendar button as
soon as you press this it generates a
dynamic date in US format month date
year then use TSA base functions to
calculate the first of the second
following month of the generated
date so the new date that has to be
entered in the edit box
here has to have the iso
format for example your initial date is
December 24
2015 then you need to calculate the
first of the second following month if
you see here what is your second
following month your second following
month
is
February
2016 right
first of your second following month and
first of the second following month that
means first day of your second following
month which is which is February
2016 for example in this case this is
25th January
2028 what is your second following month
your second following month is
March what is your first day of March
which is 01
that means this becomes
2028 which is in ISO format okay 2028
hyphen March which is
03 and what is your first day of March
01 then you need to click on this button
if it is correct yes you solve this
automation problem
successfully okay so whenever I click on
let me try again
so whenever you click this calendar
button this date keeps changing now how
can we solve this obstacle we have to
see so let us go back to our prent
St and as you all know we have we are
capturing all the objects pertaining to
each obstacle under obstacles folder so
again I'm going to right click on this
obstacles folder select scan and select
application so this is the application
that I would like to capture select the
application click on
scan now what we need to cap apture we
need to capture the
object two buttons calendar button
submission button right and then this
date field and this edit box so total
four
objects two buttons that means this is
one button where I'm generating the date
and this is my second button where I'm
submitting once I enter the date and
this is the date where I'm generating
the date correct the date field where
the date is gener where the date is
generating and then
I'm entering the date after solving the
problem which is date solution so two
buttons to edit boxes okay now let us
rename this module as has obstacle name
let's go back here this is my obstacle
name copy this and then rename this
module so it is important to rename the
module now save
your objects click on
Save and then close your xcan so let's
go back to tr and tasa if you see here
if you scroll down this is my latest
obstacle double click on this so you
should see two buttons two edit boxes
right so now let us go to left side of
the section which is blue section test
case section here let's right click on
this obstacles folder create a new test
case name with the same name of your
obstacle double click on this particular
test case now how can we solve this one
let's go back to our
presentation so first we need to create
configuration parameters let's go back
here now let's automate the test case to
automate your test case we need to drag
this module and drop onto your test
case so before we populate the values in
the test case we need to do two things
we have to create configuration
parameters for the date fields for this
field and for this field okay okay let's
go back here for that you need to go to
your module
section open the properties of the
module this is my first date generated
field here I need to create a new
configuration
parameter to instruct TSA that my target
date format is this okay for that right
click on this particular
module and
select create configuration
parameter now name this as
Target
date format so you need to make sure
that the capital letters small letters
everything matches as it is Target date
format okay let's go back to our
presentation Target date format what is
the format my format is MD y y y so here
I'm going to mention this
as
M SL d slash y y y y y y y m d y y y y
okay so this is my format and then again
the same we need to apply for date
solution which is this one right so here
here I've selected date
solution right
click create configuration
parameter
Target
date format you need to make sure the
spelling okay Target date format and now
what is the target date
format
M slash d/
y y y
y
so I have defined a standard date format
for these two date
fields okay so once that is done what we
need to do now let's go back to our test
case start automating your test case
here first you need to click on your
button correct to click click on the
button what we have to do we have to
Simply select click here click operation
click operation your action mode should
be input okay then date generated here
what we need to do we need
to capture or we need to store the date
that is generated here this date I would
like to store into a buffer first
for that what I'm going to do here inner
text I'm going to name this as
generated date this is my
buffer I'm capturing the I'm capturing
the inner text of that particular field
into a buffer your action mode should be
buffer now I captured the inner text
into your buffer called generated date
and then what we need to do and then
what we need to
do we need to use a date
expression to calculate the first day
of second month of the generated date
how can we do that here let's go back
here because we already captured the
generated date into a buffer
so here what I'm going to do open curly
braces and then month first there is a
method called month
first month first of your buffer what is
this the current date that is generated
again open curly
braces capital
B open Square
braces generated
date this is my
buffer close Square braces close curly
braces now I'm calculating the month
first of the generated date but I don't
want to calculate the first day of the
generated date I want to calculate the
first day of second month of the
generated date for that what I'm going
to do here to add so if you see here
to add month to the current date we need
to Simply use Square
braces plus 2 m I'm adding 2 months for
this particular generated date and then
here I need to specify the date
format in which I would like to enter
the date what is the date format my date
format is y y y y iph mm hyph DD so
here double quote y y y y hyphen mm
hyphen DD double clo now close your
curly
braces I'm doing closing the curly Braes
of this first month so now click on some
other place it should turn into so it
did not turn means that means there is
some problem in our code base okay so
here we forgot
to close another Square braces okay so
here month first we need to start with
the square braces basically month first
open Square brace and your buffer right
plus 2 months and then you are closing
your Square braces for this one so now
it should turn into this format okay so
what I'm doing I'm calculating the first
day of the
month what
month your generated date plus 2 months
and I'm using the format of iso format
that is what I'm calculating
here and then I'm entering the
calculated value in this particular date
solution field now let me show you see
here open curly braces month first see
here month first what is the definition
let me show you the definition is month
first date this is your date and then
you can use your offset do you want to
add one month or do you want to add a
day right and then you can specify the
format of your date so same thing now
once that is done so now you need to
click on your button which button this
button I have already entered the
date first of the second following month
of your generated date that I entered in
this particular text box now click on
this particular button here select
click now say
save now change the work state of your
test case to
completed now save the test case so let
us run this particular test case and see
what happens right click run in
scratchbook see it generated the date it
entered the
date C done
submit there is something wrong that we
are doing
20277 instead
of okay so it is calculating wrongly
let's go back here now let's go back
here and see what wrong that we are
doing okay so now I understand what is
the mistake what we are doing here so we
need not to consider inner text
basically what you can do is you can
simply specify the buffer means this
your edit box right so that's why you
can simply this date generated you can
specify the buffer here and then enter
the buffer name and also what we are
doing here right so because this is your
date it is not a text or string so your
data type should be date so we should
not
forget you need to store the value of
this particular edit box right directly
into your
buffer in the data type date save this
now let us run this particular test case
again right click and run the test case
in
scratchbook it generated a date it
entered the
date
successfully completed if you see here
what date we it
calculated 3rd of April
what is your second month from the April
which is June May June and what is the
first day which is 01 and what is the
format ISO format so your automation
problem
solved so if you have any queries leave
your queries in the comment box I'll try
to respond to your queries hope you all
understand the concept where you need to
solve for you need to solve for for an
obstacle where we have to use TSA base
functions to calculate the first day of
the second following month of the
generated date in the date field and
then the newly calculated date we have
to enter into an editable text box so
here we are using our Dynamic date
expressions and we are calculating the
calendar
date please do subscribe to the channel
click on Bell icon you'll receive
notifications whenever I publish more
videos don't forget to like and share
the video thank you
[Music]